<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo on CAnderskov - Notes To Self..</title>
    <link>https://canderskov.github.io/tags/hugo/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Hugo on CAnderskov - Notes To Self..</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <atom:link href="https://canderskov.github.io/tags/hugo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Running Hugo from github.io root</title>
      <link>https://canderskov.github.io/post/Running_Hugo_from_gitpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2017 18:19:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canderskov.github.io/post/Running_Hugo_from_gitpages/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;hugo-on-github-io-root&#34;&gt;Hugo on Github.io root&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;when follwing the official guide.. atleast, not for me.. I wanted to run it from root of my github.io account, which meant setting up the deploy of hugo following this bit: &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/#hosting-personal-organization-pages&#34;&gt;https://gohugo.io/tutorials/github-pages-blog/#hosting-personal-organization-pages&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Granted, im still getting to know git, trying out the guide over multiple attempts only gave the exact same result over and over again, the deploy script would push the changes, but push em to the hugo repo, not the github.io repo, i managed to get it to work in one gitbash session, but after restarting that i was back to square one.
This is when i started googling other results, i did find some, that did things similar to what i ended up doing was inspired heavily by the blog post here: &lt;a href=&#34;http://charliegriefer.github.io/posts/2016/07/29/hugo-on-github-pages/&#34;&gt;http://charliegriefer.github.io/posts/2016/07/29/hugo-on-github-pages/&lt;/a&gt; but instead with a slight modification of me copying and overwriting files from my hugo repo instead of rm&amp;rsquo;ing the folder posts folder, I was unsure how hugo handles files already being there when doing a build, and i figured that someday, down the line i might want to do things out of the posts directory.. which is why I modified the bash script to fit my needs. this was a quick and dirty kinda thing that i just wanted to get over with, All credit for the original script goes to @charliegriefer.github.io&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;#!/bin/bash

echo -e &amp;quot;\033[0;32mDeploying new page...\033[0m&amp;quot;

echo -e &amp;quot;\033[0;32mGenerating new html...\033[0m&amp;quot;
hugo -t hugo-redlounge

echo -e &amp;quot;\033[0;32mMoving new html to repo folder...\033[0m&amp;quot;
mv public ../canderkov.github.io
echo -e &amp;quot;\033[0;32mChanging to blog directory...\033[0m&amp;quot;
cd ../canderskov.github.io

echo -e &amp;quot;\033[0;32mCommit and push the new build...\033[0m&amp;quot;
git add --a
git commit -am &amp;quot;Site Build (`date`)&amp;quot;
git push -f origin master

echo -e &amp;quot;\033[0;32mChange back to hugo soruce...\033[0m&amp;quot;
cd ../CAnderskov-hugo

echo -e &amp;quot;\033[0;32mDeploy complete.\033[0m&amp;quot;

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hi Hugo! Nice To Meet You</title>
      <link>https://canderskov.github.io/post/HiHugoNiceToMeetYou/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 08:59:43 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://canderskov.github.io/post/HiHugoNiceToMeetYou/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h3 id=&#34;getting-to-know-hugo&#34;&gt;Getting to know Hugo&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first came across Static sites a while back, when reading something about something nerdy.. The guy writing the blog i cant remember was talking about how he finally finished migrating to jekyll.. I thought jekyll, what is that.. Ive for the longest time had the need to have a place to put notes about what i do for later use, my bookmark collection is getting out of hand, and most of the time i only use small snippets of what the bookmarked page contains, what i need is a library where i can write a short note about what ive used it for and a reference to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is that..&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why am i on Hugo and not jekyll? Well, its simple, Hugo worked, Jekyll did not.. Or rather, Jekyll worked, with the default theme, as soon as i tried to change it it went nuts about layouts not found, fixing those errors made the entire thing go completely blank.. not wanting to was countless of hours on learning this static site thing i quickly moved on to look for alternatives.. Queue Hugo.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;setting-up-hugo&#34;&gt;Setting up Hugo&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download hugo executable from &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/spf13/hugo/releases&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add hugo to path or add the directory with hugo.exe to path (the latter did not work for me, so i put the exe in a folder already in path seeing as my patiance was very short in getting Windows to not be Windows.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Download a theme from &lt;a href=&#34;http://themes.gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Figure out and get to know Markdown and you are all set.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;quick-tips&#34;&gt;Quick tips&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Get gitbash, get used to it, never go back to windows cmd.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server -w&lt;/code&gt; in a gitbash while you write your pages will auto update every time you save&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you are switching themes &lt;code&gt;hugo server -w&lt;/code&gt; needs to be restarted it will not update correctly, same goes for update to the index pages.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Current theme: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/tmaiaroto/hugo-redlounge&#34;&gt;https://github.com/tmaiaroto/hugo-redlounge&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>